《超女》前情提要
Previously on Supergirl...
为了拯救未来  我帮助莱克斯把你带了回来
I helped Lex bring you back for the sake of the future.
另一个布莱尼亚克告诉我必须
Another Brainiac told me that it was absolutely critical
要帮莱克斯保密
that I help Lex in complete secrecy.
也许这对你来说为时已晚  父亲
Yes, it may be too late for you, Father,
但是我很快就能实现你没做到的
but soon I will accomplish what you could not.
我会永生
I will live forever.
都吃四十二块了
Forty-two!
什么  三十世纪可没这些东西
What? They don't have these in the 30th century.
我可以去帮你做一些
I can get out to make you up a bunch
如果你想  你还可以带回去
and you can take 'em with you if you like.
或者你可以吃到厨房料用完
Or you can just keep eating until the kitchen runs out.
那你就可以多待一首歌的时间
Then you'd be able to stay for one more song.
军团飞船充好电我就走
Once the Legion ship has power, I gotta go.
说到军团  你还没告诉我们的你军团称号
Speaking of which, you never told us what your Legion call sign is.
-没有吗  -没有
- I didn't? - No.
这不重要
It's not a big deal.
开玩笑
Are you kidding?
布莱尼说
Uh, according to Brainy,
军团成员穿上制服前
before every Legion member puts on his vestments,
都要取一个称号
he must have a call sign.
"技术宅"
"Computer Lad."
-什么  -这比给凯特·格兰特当技术员
- What? - You know, it's a hop, skip, and a jump
不知道厉害到哪里去了
from Cat Grant's IT guy.
你为什么要叫"技术宅"
Why is "Computer Lad" Your name?
这确实比不上"火星猎人"
It's not "Martian Manhunter" or whatever, sure,
但军团成员的名字描述的就是这个人
but Legionnaires' names speak to who they are, right?
化学王有化学的力量
So, Chemical King has power for chemicals,
闪电妞能控制电
Lightning Lass controls electricity.
有一天  我的小舅子决定叫我"技术宅"
One day, my brother-in-law decides to call me "Computer Lad,"
就保留下来了
and it kind of stuck.
说不好  我还挺喜欢的
And, I don't know, I kind of like it.
-好吧  -还不错
- Okay. - It's nice.
-卡拉  -怎么
- Kara. - Yeah.
你邀请了威廉
You invited William.
没什么
It... It's nothing.
游戏之夜后  不能不邀请吧
After game night, I couldn't not.
卡拉OK通宵  来吧  各位
Karaoke's all night, so come on up, guys.
卡拉  你没告诉我是卡拉OK之夜
Kara, you didn't tell me it was karaoke night.
你喜欢卡拉OK吗
Is karaoke your thing?
你显然没听过我唱托托的《非洲》
Clearly, you've never heard my rendition of "Africa" By Toto.
卡拉威胁要唱这首歌很久了
Kara has been threatening to do that one for a long time.
-我没有  -那不如我们一起唱吧
- I haven't. - So, we're gonna do it together?
*他转向我  似乎要说*
*He turned to me as if to say*
*快点  在等着你呢*
*Hurry, boy It's waiting there for you*
*我绝不会轻易离开你*
*It's gonna take a lot to drag me away from you*
*即便千千万万人*
*There's nothing that a hundred men or more*
*也无法做到*
*Could ever do*
*愿甘霖降非洲*
*I bless the rains down in Africa*
*愿甘霖*
*I bless the rains...*
厉害  卡拉
Yeah, Kara!
*我们从未拥有*
*The things we never had*
没错
Oh, that's right.
好
Yes!
看她在他旁边那个劲
Oh, look at her on his side.
*野狗*
*The wild dogs...*
演一下  *在夜里嚎叫*
Act it out. *Cry out in the night*
*它们似乎不眠  渴求孤独*
*As they grow restless longing for some solitary...*
我听说莱克斯偷偷越过政府安保
I heard about Lex sneaking past the government security
调查军团飞船
to probe the Legion ship.
他肯定把你逼疯了
He must be driving you crazy.
连温都没找到飞船上的蹊跷
I mean, not even Winn could find anything unturned on the ship.
我知道他有所图谋
I know that he is up to something.
所以我往超查部网络上传了监视软件
Which is why I uploaded some spyware onto my DEO Internet.
无论他做什么  我都可以看到
That way, whatever he does, I will see.
艾丽克斯  我很骄傲你留下为正义而战
Alex, I'm proud of you for staying to fight the good fight,
但我也有担心
but I do worry.
好吧  没有必要
Well, you don't have to
因为我能处理好
because I can handle myself.
而且  布莱尼会帮我
And, plus, Brainy's got my back.
卢瑟先生
Mr. Luthor.
我给你上传了杰玛·库珀的资料
I uploaded you the file on Gemma Cooper.
很好  你现在有空去解决
Excellent. Now you're free to help with
艾丽克斯·丹弗斯这个问题了
the Alex Danvers problem.
问题
Problem?
她好像在监视我
She's been spying on me.
她还没妨碍到我们的工作
She hasn't interfered with our work,
但如果妨碍了
but if she does,
我们得采取一劳永逸的办法
it might require more permanent actions.
帮她控制住自己
Help her control herself.
没有什么麻烦了吧
Now, is everything quiet there?
当然
Of course.
没有干扰或技术难题吗
No disruptions or technical difficulties?
没有
No.
很好
Good.
随时给我汇报
Keep me posted.
我来了
I'm on my way.
超查部有情况
911 at the DEO.
-我去跟进  -我跟你一起
- I'll track it. - Oh. I... I'll join you.
我以为你要走了
I thought you were leaving.
你们帮了我
You guys bailed me out.
不帮你们我是不会走的
No, I'm not leaving this center without repaying you.
你真是个全才
What don't you do well?
开玩笑吗
Are you kidding me?
那和声  你怎么做到的
With those harmonies? Where did that come from?
有你这样的搭档  很简单
With a partner like you, it's easy.
你
Would you, uh...
你有空想不想出去
Would you like to go out sometime?
就我俩
Just us.
约会那种
Like a date?
约会
A date.
你觉得呢
What do you think?
超...
Hey, Super--
卡拉
Kara.
她超厉害
She is super.
是的
Sure.
艾丽克斯要你去你祖母家
Alex needs you at... your grandmother's house.
你超...亲爱的
You know, your D... ear...
奶奶的家  马上
Old Gran Gran's house, like, immediately.
没什么事吧
Is everything all right?
没事  她只是最近一直不舒服
Yeah. She's just been feeling under the weather.
我该走了
I should really go.
-行  -我很抱歉
- Yeah. - I'm so sorry.
通讯器怎么会放这个
How is that coming through our comms?
我小时候常在店里听到这首歌
I used to listen to this song in the shop when I was a kid...
跟我爸一起时
with my dad.
慢着  你的意思是
Okay, wait, so you're saying...
我觉得玩具人回来了
I think Toyman's back.
超 女
第五季 第十二集
什么意思  不是玩具人引起的故障
What do you mean, not a bug from Toyman?
还有什么可能
What else could it be?
一开始  我以为这么多无人机
Initially, I thought the drone outburst
只是因为监视软件的恶意代码
was just some bad code in our surveillance software,
但这个
but this,
这个遍布我们的系统
this is in our whole system.
是病毒吗
So, it's a virus?
更像是人工智能
More like artificial intelligence.
这就是他播放那首歌的原因
Whoa, that's why he was playing the song.
这是我爸
This is my dad.
他生前的最后一项研究就是这个
The last thing that he was working on was a version of this.
把他的意识植入数码空间的办法
A way to put his whole mind into the digital space.
他  他想成为超意识
He... He wanted to become hyper conscious.
如果他能在万维网里永生
If he could become immortal in the World Wide Web,
他就会成为终极乐园的终极玩家
he would be the ultimate player in the ultimate playground.
到那种地步  他就能为所欲为了
Once there, he could commit any act of violence.
任何时间地点
Any time, any place,
空中交通  医院  美国核指挥部
air traffic, hospitals, US Nuclear Command.
但你说你爸一直在开发
But you said your dad was still working on it, so--
而且  这个玩具人不是他
And, plus, this Toyman isn't him,
他怎么会做你爸想做的事
okay, so how could he be doing what your father was trying to do?
眼镜  这个玩具人有黑曜石白金隐形眼镜
Lenses. This Toyman has the Obsidian Platinum lenses.
储存库  调出项目906016
Storage vault. Bring up item 906016.
关于这段与玩具人最终的见面视频  我有些发现
I noted something on this video of our final meeting with Toyman.
这里
There.
看  玩具人用了黑曜石镜片
See, Toyman uses the Obsidian lenses
把自己下载到了笔记本电脑上
to download himself onto a laptop.
我们不是没收了那台电脑  带回这儿了吗
Didn't we confiscate the laptop and bring it back here?
硬件没问题  但有一个分开的驱动
The hardware's clean but there's a compartmentalized drive.
能让它看起来像关了  但其实还在运行
That would make it appear to be off while still working.
玩具人找到了办法入侵我们的网络
Toyman found a way to leap into our Internet
绕过超查部的防火墙传到外部
and bypass the DEO's firewall to the outside.
好吧  我们有办法解决吗
Okay, so do we have a fix for this?
有  我爸的代码
Yeah. My dad's code.
我觉得我能进行逆转工程  将其变为杀毒代码
I think I can reverse-engineer it into a kill code.
封锁
Lockdown.
封锁模式启动
封锁
Lockdown.
你们难道不知道
Don't you guys know it's rude
在背后议论别人不礼貌吗
to talk about someone behind their back?
玩具人
Toyman?
告诉我这只是一段视频
Okay, tell me this is a video, guys.
不  我不再是以往的形态了
Oh, no, I am everything I used to be,
我现在是电子的  永生的
but electronic and immortal.
立刻将超查部的网络对万维网开放
Now, lower the DEO's firewall to the World Wide Web
不然我就用你们所有的玩具杀掉你们
or I will use all of your toys to kill you.
激光安全系统已启动
他控制了我们的激光防御系统
He's taking control of our laser defenses.
激光安全系统
你解除了吗
Did you kill it?
没有  我只是把他从指挥中心里弄出去了
No. I just knocked him out of the command center.
就是说他还可以回来吗
So he can come back?
是的  他会的
Oh, he can, and will.
好了
Okay.
我要大家整合这东西能用来对付我们的设备
I want us to round up every item this thing can use against us,
枪和通信设备
guns, comm links,
任何能连接我们网络的蓝牙设备
anything with a Bluetooth that can connect to our Internet,
我要这些全都撤走
and I want it evacuated.
只要这里有人工智能可以使用的科技
As long as there's technology here this AI can access,
我们就是坐以待毙
we are sitting ducks.
去吧
Go.
我也会去整合一下装备
I'll gather gear too.
一旦我们集齐一切
Once we've got everything,
我就可以带着它们飞出玩具人的信号范围外
I can fly it outside of Toyman's signal range.
好
Okay.
布莱尼  你能隔离人工智能吗
Brainy, can you isolate the AI?
我把他从指挥中心里
I pushed him down from the command center
逼到虚拟盖下的服务器端
to the server level under a virtual lid.
但是他还在想尽办法攻进来
But he's still fighting to get back up here.
你看
Look.
如果他攻破了虚拟盖怎么办
Well, what if he breaks through the lid?
有92.6%的几率
There is a 92.6% chance
他会进入万维网
he'll make his way onto the World Wide Web.
等他进去之后  他就无所不能了
When he's there, he can attack... everything.
如果让超女进入服务器端
Okay, well, what if Supergirl goes down to the server level
把一切都毁掉呢
and fries everything?
服务器在超查部能源中心的最上层
The servers are located on top of the DEO's power core.
如果它们毁了  能源中心也毁了
If they melt, so does the core.
而且会使方圆4.8公里内的生命全都蒸发掉
It would vaporize all life within a three-mile radius.
你们听到了吗  是老式电话在响吗
Do you hear that? Is that an old-fashioned telephone?
好
Okay.
丹弗斯局长  我的超查部今晚为什么关闭了
Director Danvers, why is my DEO on lockdown tonight?
是因为玩具人  长官
It's Toyman, sir.
玩具人
Toyman?
他不是死了吗
I thought he was dead.
是的  但是显然他把自己上传到我们的系统
Yes, well, apparently, he has uploaded himself into our system.
让我们攻其不备
It took us all completely by surprise.
看出来了
Clearly.
你能隔绝人工智能吗
Can you sequester the AI?
世界最不想看到的是失常玩具人在网络上捣蛋
The last thing this world needs is a rogue Toyman on the Web.
我们正在想办法
We're trying.
在这同时  为了以防万一
And in the meantime, just in case,
我在整合我们所有的智能科技
I'm gathering all of our smart tech
立刻让超女带着飞离信号范围外
to have Supergirl fly it out immediately.
我知道这很冒险
I know it's a risk,
但唯有她能胜任这项任务
but if anyone can do the job, it's her.
但是她不行
But she can't.
提醒你一下
In case you've forgotten,
失常的氪星人之前有袭击过我们地球
rogue Kryptonians have attacked our planet before.
超查局有氪星防护装置
The DEO has Kryptonite safeguards in place,
不行  防护装置绝对不能关闭
and, no, they cannot be disabled.
我们有反氪星技术来保护她
Well, we have anti-Kryptonite technology to protect her.
你说的是在另一个时间发生的事吧
I think you're remembering that from another time.
也许是在另一个地球上
Another Earth, perhaps.
我有一个轮班组
I have a split shift crew.
你想让我们十二个人在整个超查部里
You want the 12 of us to go around the entire DEO
拆除所有的科技设备
to dismantle all of our tech
希望玩具人不会在此期间重新获得控制权吗
and hope that Toyman doesn't regain control while we do it?
国家安全是我们的首要责任
National safety is our primary responsibility,
所以你必须竭尽全力
and that is why you have to do everything in your power
消灭它  不让其扩散
to neutralize that thing and not let it get out.
明白了吗
Are we understood?
明白  长官
Yes, sir.
很好  有情况通知我
Good. Keep me posted.
温
Winn.
多克斯特工  我还在想你什么会打电话给我
Agent Dox. I was wondering when you'd call.
你早就知道玩具人会将自己上传到超查部
You knew Toyman would upload himself into the DEO.
我的推理是正确的  没错
I correctly theorized it, yes.
但是你没告诉我
And you didn't tell me.
需要的时候才会知道
It was need-to-know.
现在你知道了
And now that you do know,
你要知道  我要你帮我找到玩具人的代码
you need to know, I want you to get me Toyman's code.
玩具人用来把自己输进电脑的代码
What Toyman used to put himself into the computer.
为什么
Why?
这样我们就能对利维坦施以其人之道
So we can beat Leviathan at their own game.
他们是这个星球面临最大的威胁
They are the greatest threat this planet faces.
而且你想要他们的长生不老
And you want their immortality.
这是他们唯一胜我一筹的地方
It's the one advantage they have over me.
有了这个代码  我就可以与之势均力敌
With this code, I can level the playing field.
只要你能保证没人在监视
As soon as you can make sure no one is watching,
取得并复制玩具人的代码
access Toyman's code and copy it.
等你搞定了
Once you are done,
你就会让我们离拯救世界更近一步
you'll have gotten us one step closer to saving the world.
这是什么情况
What was that?
我以前从来不会对龙虾过敏
I've never been allergic to lobster before.
隐形眼镜上的生物连接依然不起作用
The Bio-Link on the lenses still isn't working.
吃东西还能为身体提供营养
Look, eating virtually still provides the body with nutrients,
但是这个接口过度刺激了身体的感官反应
but the interface is hyper-stimulating the body's sensor reaction
使其变成一种中毒性休克
into a kind of toxic shock.
上周  我们几乎完善了白金黑曜石
Last week, we were this close to perfecting Obsidian Platinum.
我们要解决这个问题
We need to fix this.
罗哈斯小姐
Miss Rojas,
莉娜·卢瑟在你的办公室等你
Lena Luthor is waiting in your office.
莉娜
Lena.
一周造访两次
Twice in one week.
就像以前一样
It's getting to be like old times.
我知道你在为白金发布会做准备
Well, I know you're gearing up for the Platinum launch
我希望能先预览一下
and I was hoping I could get a preview.
我很喜欢你的第一代隐形眼镜
I loved your first-generation lenses.
它在很多方面都有帮到我
They were helpful to me in so many ways.
所以我是否可以先睹为快
So maybe I could get a peek?
当然
Of course.
但是我们还没完全准备好
Except, we're not quite ready yet.
一切都还顺利吧
Is everything all right?
是的  没什么大问题  只是...
Yes, nothing major. Just, uh...
生物连接算法上还有个小问题
a small issue with the Bio-Link algorithm.
听起来不妙
Oh, that doesn't sound good.
也许我可以帮忙
You know, maybe I can help.
卢瑟公司一直在和五角大楼
Luthor Corp's been working
研发一个全新的神经接口
with the Pentagon on a new neural interface.
我们刚开发了一种特殊的处理器
We've just developed a special processor
可以跨越宽频谱调节生物连接
that regulates Bio-Linking across a wide spectrum.
完全消除反馈环路
It's completely eliminated the feedback loop,
解决大部分的副作用
gotten most of the side effects.
真厉害  但是我们不在五角大楼
Well, that's impressive, but we're not the Pentagon.
那是好事  五角大楼刚刚退出了
And that's a good thing. The Pentagon just dropped out,
给你留了一个也许是最完美的接口
leaving us with perhaps the perfect interface for you.
你怎么看
So what do you say?
我们帮助黑曜石之北彻底改变虚拟现实吧
We help Obsidian North revolutionize virtual reality?
谢谢你的提议
I appreciate the offer,
但我们上一次的合作
but our last attempt at collaboration
差点毁掉我们之间的一切关系
almost ruined everything between us.
我不想再冒险
I don't wanna risk that.
你说得对
You're right.
但如果你改变主意  通知我
But let me know if you change your mind.
提议依然有效
The offer still stands.
我会的
I will.
我认为人工智能只会出现在一个地方
There is only one place I think the AI can be.
下层地下室走廊的一个主服务器塔
In a prime server tower down in the sub-basement corridor.
要找出玩具人所在服务器的办法
Now, the way that we find which server the Toyman is on,
就是亲自到走廊里去找
is to physically go down into the corridors and search for it.
幸好我们的仓库里有这个
Luckily, we had this in storage.
凡埃克辐射扫描仪
Van Eck radiation scanner.
它没有与我们的网络连接
It's delinked from our Internet
并且能够区分
and able to distinguish
正常服务器辐射和异常辐射
between normal server radiation and abnormal radiation,
从而让我们找出玩具人的位置
thereby allowing us to pinpoint Toyman.
因此我要去走廊
Accordingly, I shall head into the corridors.
不  布莱尼  我们需要你坐镇这里
No, Brainy, we need you up here
以防玩具人想再次进入我们的指挥中心
in case Toyman tries to get in the command center again.
我去
I'll go.
我也一起去
Not without me.
你确定你可以去
Are you sure you're up for this?
这是我的敌人
This is my enemy.
是我要解决的问题
It's my problem.
而且我是唯一知道代码的人
Plus, I'm the only one that knows the code.
好吧
Okay, fine.
温和超女去搜索服务器
Winn, Supergirl, go for the servers,
布莱尼  你将他困在数字化的网络里
Brainy, you keep him at bay digitally,
我会保证
and I will make sure
他接触不到我们的任何技术
that he doesn't get ahold of any of our tech.
说来好笑
You know, it's so funny
因为我们有这些监控器和监听器
because we have all these eyes and ears in there
在不间断地监视和监听  但是...
looking and listening all the time, but...
到底是谁在监控谁
who is watching who?
布莱尼
Brainy.
我要知道
I need to know.
这是莱克斯计划的另一步吗
Is this another step in one of Lex's plans?
莱克斯的确帮忙操作让玩具人出现在网络里
Lex did help manipulate Toyman's digital reemergence
但是我和这件事毫无关系
but I had nothing to do with it.
为了将来  我必须帮助莱克斯
Helping Lex is what I have to do for the sake of the future.
你知道的
You know that.
还是那句话  我保证
Still, I promise
一切都在我掌握中
I have everything under control.
好
Okay.
我会相信你
I am trusting you.
双份意式特浓咖啡
Doppio espresso.
让你开心点
To cheer you up?
为什么觉得我不开心
What makes you think I need cheering up?
你要发展你的宏大项目
Well, you're trying to advance your grand project.
档案魔方的Q波虽然有用
The Q waves from the archive cube had helped,
但是下一步还
but the next step remains...
没有头绪
elusive.
莱克斯还会关心别人的情绪
A Lex who cares about the emotional state of others.
这真是一个全新的世界
This really is a whole new world.
我关心是因为我们有共同的目标
I care because your goals are my goals.
最终目的都是为了你自己是吧
Ah, it does always come back to you, doesn't it?
不过没错  除了实地试验
But, yes, with the exception of field testing,
我的零伤害算法差不多完成了
my Non Nocere algorithm is almost ready.
只是
Just...
还需要一个发散装置
need a distribution device
能在短时间内发散到尽可能多的人那里
so I can get it to as many people as possible all at once.
本以为今晚能和安德里亚协商好  可是
I thought I'd come to an agreement with Andrea this evening, but--
她拒绝了
She said no.
说实话  安德里亚向来都不太有远见
I have to say, Andrea was always a bit short-sighted.
我能帮到什么吗
Perhaps there's something I can do?
用不着杀人  莱克斯
I don't need anyone murdered, Lex.
我还有别的技能
I have other skill sets.
而且  我们是搭档
Plus, we're partners.
让我帮你
Let me help.
等下  你是在征求我的同意吗
Wait, are you actually asking my permission?
这是个全新的世界
It's a whole new world.
Q波发散模拟失败
行吧
Fine.
真行
Nice one.
我尽力了
Well, I try.
我只是希望你不用
I just wish you didn't have to
为了我爸的疯狂世界大噩梦
on account of my dad's global insanity nightmare--
不是你的错
It's not your fault.
其实算是我的错
Actually, it kinda is.
我跟你们说  我还记得我爸的代码
When I told you guys that I remembered my dad's code,
那其实是我编的
I'm the one that came up with it.
我本来以为挺酷的
Look, I thought it would be cool.
要是能让真人进入游戏里
Why just play a video game,
还玩什么电子游戏  对吧
you know, when you can be inside of one?
我经常半夜不睡  就在想用不同的方式
I'd stay up past midnight trying to think of different ways
解释普雷马克有关心灵的理论
to express Premack's theory
记在一本蓝色小笔记本上
of the mind in this little blue notebook.
我爸后来发现了  问我这是什么
My dad finally caught me with it and asked me what it was.
我以为他生气了  可是他好像...
I thought he was getting mad, but he seemed...
很骄傲
He seemed proud.
当然  现在我知道那不是骄傲  是贪婪
Of course, now I know it wasn't pride, it was greed.
警察把他抓走的那晚
The night the police finally came and took him away,
我去找那本子
I went to look for the notebook.
已经不见了
It was gone.
其实是他拿走了
Turns out that he had taken it
还在原来的位置放了一个玩具猴子
and left in its place a little toy monkey.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
没事  我们说点别的
Ah, it... It's fine. Let's talk about something else.
你和威廉
You and William.
-怎么回事  -什么
- What's with that? - What?
我搞砸了他跟你的约会
I totally messed him asking you out.
-什么  不不  才不是  -被我搞砸了
- What? No, no. That was not... - I messed that up.
他没有要...
Well, he wasn't...
-我们...什么也没有  -怎么可能
- There's... There is nothing there. - What?
抱歉  但就算是在三十世纪
I'm sorry, but even in the 30th century,
唱出那么优美的和声
harmonizing that beautifully with someone
两个人之间绝对有火花
is a definitive sign of something there.
我可能是喜欢他  但我...也不知道
Maybe I like him. I don't... I don't know.
说实话
The truth is,
就凭我的身份和我隐藏的秘密
given who I am and the secrets I keep,
我都不确定自己该不该恋爱
I'm not sure I can even have a relationship.
我的双重身份破坏了我和莉娜的友谊
My double life blew up my friendship with Lena.
更何况是跟人谈恋爱呢
So how am I supposed to date someone?
莉娜有那样的反应
Just because Lena reacted the way that she did
并不代表别人也一样
does not mean that other people will.
可能吧  但我不希望我们的关系建立在谎言上
Maybe so, but I refuse to start any relationship on a lie.
威廉只是约了你一回  卡拉
William asked you out on one date, Kara.
你又不知道你们会不会发展恋情
You don't even know if it's gonna go anywhere,
你不试试怎么会知道
but you won't find out unless you try.
要是成了  你就...
And then if it does, you know, just...
一步一步来
take it one step at a time.
One step at a time, huh?
没错
That's right.
我们已经排查了控制中心
So we've got the command center cleared.
但假如玩具人回来
But if Toyman comes back,
绝不能让数据化的他控制任何东西
we cannot let him get his digital hands on any of this.
一队 去除所有智能枪里的芯片
So, Squad 1, I want you to pop the chips out of every smart gun.
二队  去除所有通讯设备里的芯片
Squad 2, do the same with communication tech.
三队  断开一切连接
Squad 3, delink everything else.
我们已经考虑周全了吧
We've really outsmarted ourselves here, haven't we?
好  去工作吧
All right, get to work.
你们继续
Everyone, keep working.
我去检查
I'll check it out.
非法入侵
Breach!
玩具人应该在这边
I think Toyman's this way.
玩具人
Toyman?
温斯洛
Winslow.
你终于来了
At last you're here.
爸
Dad.
这首歌  我  我知道是你
The song. I... I knew it was you?
温  我必须引起你的注意
Winn, I had to get your attention.
恭喜你做到了
Oh, you got my attention.
-不不不  我是来帮忙的  -别
- No, no. I'm here to help. - No. Don't.
你说
Explain yourself.
温知道  我的梦想就是将我的意识数字化
Winn knows. Digitizing my consciousness was my dream.
是  你偷来的梦想
Yeah. A dream you stole.
行吧  但另一个温数字化时
Fine. But when that other Winn digitized himself,
用的是我写的代码和我的硬件
he used the underlying code that I'd written, plus my hardware.
我现在翻译出了80%的自己
Now, I managed to translate 80% of myself,
但他肯定用了某种未来科技将我们匹配起来
but he must have paired it with some sort of future tech,
他一上线  我也上线了
because when he came online, I did too.
于是你就想帮我们
And now you wanna help us?
对  我被困在备份驱动器里
Yes. I'm trapped in a backup drive,
只有你们放我出来  我才能行动
and the only way I can do anything is if you release me.
抱歉  你是疯了吗
I'm sorry. Are you insane?
等等  没错
Oh, wait, yes.
根据诊断  你确实疯了
Clinically, you are.
我们要是放了他  他就会到处作乱
If we let him go, he will do what he always does
像他以前那样
and wreak havoc everywhere.
才不是
That's not true!
是  我原本的计划是这样
I mean, it was my original plan,
但另一个温
but this other Winn is
他计划的事情更加出格
planning to do things that are beyond the pale.
我在他的代码里看到了
I've seen it in his code.
很好  所以我要把你们俩都删除
Yeah, well, that's why I'm going to delete both of you.
但我想帮忙
But I wanna help.
而凭你们也打败不了他
And you can't beat him alone.
超女  温
Supergirl, Winn,
玩具人的三个哨兵
apparently, three of Toyman's
现在正往你们那里去
sentries are headed for you as we speak.
什么哨兵
What kind of sentries?
玩具人的人工智能入侵我们的网络前
It seems that before Toyman's AI got into our net,
还入侵了飞猴
it got into some flying monkeys.
超女  走这边
Supergirl, go this way.
这边安全
You'll be safe.
不  你骗不了我们  永远都别想
No, no, you are not fooling us. Not now, not ever.
这堵墙后面有条服务通道
There is a service corridor behind this wall.
温斯洛  不要
Winslow, no!
抱歉在这个时候过来打扰
Forgive my boldness at this hour.
在那边看见你  我就想着必须抓住机会
It's just I saw you across the room and knew I had to pounce.
莱克斯·卢瑟
Lex Luthor.
你抓住机会的时候应该警惕一点
You should be careful where you pounce.
你不清楚可能碰上什么
You never know what you might find.
不过我确实认识你
Oh, but I do know who you are.
杰玛·库珀
Gemma Cooper.
黑曜石之北的董事长
Board chair of Obsidian North,
著名计算机科学家  擅长品酒  鉴马
renowned computer scientist with excellent taste in wine, horses,
挑选商业机会
and business opportunities.
什么机会
What kind of opportunities?
让黑曜石之北和卢瑟集团相得益彰的机会
The kind that can satisfy both Obsidian North and Luthor Corp.
好笑  我们两家公司似乎并没有相似之处
Funny. I don't think there is much we had in common.
我以为像你这样有见识有远见的女人
I'd think a woman of your vision and insight
能透过表面看实质
would be able to see past the superficial.
你们白金黑曜石简介链接的界面还有问题
You have an interface issue with the Obsidian Platinum Bio-Link.
今天我妹妹提出可以修好它
Today, my sister offered to help fix it.
你们的首席执行官拒绝了
Your CEO rejected her offer
因为她的情感影响了她的商业行为
because she let her feelings determine her business moves,
我以为你能明智一些
and I think you're smarter than that.
你想让我们跟卢瑟集团扯上关系
You're suggesting that we get into bed with Luther Corp?
这怎么能算明智
Since when is that smart?
只要你在这地球上做生意  这就是明智的
Whenever it comes to doing business anywhere on this planet.
你们有出色的科技
You have amazing technology--
至少差点就有了
At least you almost do.
而我们有盟友  资产
We have allies and assets,
政府密探  支持者  遍布全球
government stooges and supporters in every corner of the globe.
打个响指就调动这些资源
That's the kind of reach you can't get
你们是做不到的
with just a snap of your fingers.
所以说  你们有潜力
So you have the potential,
而我们能帮你实现
but we can help you realize it.
那要是帮了我们  你们想要什么回报
And what do you expect to get back in exchange for this "help"?
科技领域能容纳的企业有限
The tech field can only hold so many players.
我们迟早要为了这一席之地竞争
Sooner or later, there might not be room for the both of us.
既然能强强联手
Why be at each other's throats
又何必争个你死我活
when we could be joined at the hip?
谁知道呢
Who knows,
联手说不定会愉快
we might like it.
我愿意的时候
I can be an excellent friend
我可以是很好的朋友
when I want to be.
而我确实想当你的朋友
And I do want to be your friend...
很久很久
for a long time.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
我知道你上次见到你父亲很不愉快
I know the last time you saw your father was pretty horrible.
每次信任他都没有好结果
Trusting him never leads to anything good.
我理解  但是"每次"是个很绝对的词
I get that, but "never" is a big word.
荣恩之前发现他跟他弟弟有血海深仇
J'onn recently found himself in a blood feud with his brother
他曾说他们永远无法和好
where he said they would never make amends,
可现在他们成了互帮互助的兄弟
and now they're brothers that support each other.
好吧  那挺好的
Yeah, well, good for J'onn,
但我不会信任一号或二号玩具人
but I am not trusting Toyman No. 1 or 2
除非他们都被删除
until they are both deleted.
丹弗斯局长
Director Danvers,
其余平板电脑都断开了链接
the rest of the tablets have been delinked.
是否需要帮您断开
Permission to delink yours?
没关系  我来就好  谢谢
No, I'll take care of that, thank you.
授权行为  终止程序
怎么回事
You son of a...
正在拷贝
布莱尼
Brainy.
你在我的账户上干什么
What the hell were you doing in my account?
我信任你才把间谍软件交给你
I trusted you with that spyware.
你却黑进了我的平板电脑
And you hacked into my tablet
覆写了我的指令  然后删除了
and you overrode my commands and you deleted it.
告诉我  我说错了
Just tell me I'm wrong!
你没说错
You're not wrong.
确实是我干的
I did it.
我就知道
I knew it.
你知道吗
You know what?
自从其他布莱尼
Ever since those other Brainys
让你不再佩戴抑制器之后
got you to take off your inhibitors,
你就跟以前不一样了
you have been acting different,
而且这不是性格上的变化
and it's not some personality different.
好像是你在隐瞒什么
It's like you're hiding something.
好像你有个什么秘密计划
Like you've got some secret plan.
我那样做是为了保护你  艾丽克斯
I did it to protect you, Alex.
少来吧
Come on.
莱克斯发现你的间谍软件只是时间问题
Sooner or later, Lex would have found your spyware,
他可以反追踪到你的账户
he would have traced it back to your account--
我知道有风险
I knew the risk.
这不是风险  这是事实
It isn't a risk, it's a fact.
如果说玩具人的失败教会了我们什么
Look, if this Toyman fiasco's taught us anything,
那就是任何技术  无论有多高明
it's that technology, no matter how sophisticated,
都能被用来伤害我们
can be used against us.
只是时间问题
It's just a matter of when.
我应该提前告诉你的
I should have told you first.
但是我拒绝让莱克斯针对你
But I refuse to let Lex come after you.
白金黑曜石生物连接升级  超强刺激
中毒性休克
杰玛
Gemma.
一切还好吗
Is everything all right?
很明显不好
Apparently not.
据莱克斯·卢瑟所说  我们的接口出了问题
According to Lex Luthor, our interface isn't working,
而且产生了严重后果
and it's generating catastrophic results.
这话说得有点夸张
Um, look, that's an overstatement.
而且当时给过你机会
And when you were given the opportunity
与他们共同解决这个问题
to team up with them to fix this issue,
你拒绝了
you passed.
卢瑟家的人也许有轻微的技术优势  但是
The Luthors may have a slight scientific edge, but...
我和莉娜的关系并不友好
Lena and I have not had the best relationship in the past.
这跟你和莉娜的关系无关
This isn't about your friendship with Lena.
而是让你专注于
It's about staying focused on the business
你的父亲究其一生打造的事业
that your father spent his life building,
在你的努力下  眼看就要实现
that you yourself have brought to the precipice
史上最大的技术突破
of one of the biggest tech advancements in history.
我知道现状如何
I know where we stand.
那我就不需要提醒你
Then I don't need to remind you
你为了走到这一步
of all the other relationships you've abandoned
抛弃了多少关系
to get this where it needs to be.
卢瑟一家能帮我们
The Luthors can help us.
在大学时
In college,
我之所以答应当你的导师
when I agreed to be your mentor,
是因为我相信你永远不会退缩
it was because I believed you would never back down.
也许我想错了
Maybe I was wrong.
莉娜·卢瑟
莉娜
Lena?
我是安德里亚
It's Andrea.
我改变主意了
I think I've changed my mind.
就是这个
This is it.
玩具人的主服务器
Toyman's prime server.
现在怎么办
So, what happens now?
点击几下
In a few clicks,
一切就结束了
this will all be over.
还好吗
Is everything okay?
代码输入不进去
Code is not entering.
布莱尼
Brainy.
-你找到服务器了吗  -找到了
- Have you found the server? - Yeah, we did,
但是遇到了问题
but we're having a problem.
什么问题
What is it?
每次我想输入终止代码的时候
Every time I try to enter the kill code,
总会被弹回来
it keeps getting bounced back.
看来玩具人的人工智能已经强大到
It seems Toyman's AI is growing too strong for you
无法从服务器外部进入了
to access it anywhere outside the server.
那我们该如何进入呢
But how else do we access it?
我必须得进去
I have to go inside it.
这是军团飞船上的
I have this from the Legion ship.
它可以让我短期内进入数据空间
It allows me to enter the digital space temporarily.
如果你进去的话  会不会遇到...
If you go inside it, can't you run into--
我爸  或者玩具人  或者都遇到
My dad, or Toyman, or... both.
是啊
Yeah.
什么声音
What was that?
我们有莱克斯奥服吗
We have Lexosuits?
玩具人的人工智能在控制  快跑
Toyman's AI is inside of them. Get out now.
他们想跑
They're breaking out.
玩具人的技术想逃跑
Toyman's tech is trying to escape.
如果成功了
If it succeeds,
那么玩具人
there is a 100% chance
绝对可以让整个因特网变成武器
that Toyman will be able to weaponize the entire Internet.
你去吧  我能做到
Go. I can do this.
-但你父亲...  -不过是代码而已
- But your father-- It's only code, okay?
这个很简单  我进去
And this is simple. I go to it,
输入终止代码  再出来  我能做到
I enter the kill code, and then I get out. I can do this.
我必须做到
I mean, I have to do this.
别忘了
Don't forget...
我可是"技术宅"
I'm Computer Lad.
好了  有哪里不对劲
Okay, what doesn't belong?
找到了
Gotcha.
温
Winn!
你不该一个人待在这里
You... You shouldn't be in here by yourself.
你没办法一个人阻止他的
You won't be able to hold him back alone.
你需要我
You need me!
我不需要你
I do not need you!
抓到你啦
Tag!
我就知道
I knew it.
打开门  把掌锁打开  儿子
Open the door. Give me the palm lock, son.
伸手打开就好
Just reach up and do it.
相信我  我已经改过自新了
Trust me, I've... I've changed!
你不能信任他
You can't trust him.
我做这一切都是为了他
I did all of this for him,
你看看他是怎么对我的
and look how he treats me.
那是因为你是个变态
That's because you're a psycho!
我扶着你  我扶你
I got you. I got you.
超女  你得离开这里
Supergirl, you have to get away from here.
我不会退出这场战斗
I'm not leaving this fight.
别傻了  现在可不是坚持原则的时候
Don't be crazy. This isn't some time to stick to some code.
除非你是他们
Unless you're them.
玩具人也许在控制我们的技术
Toyman may be controlling our technology,
但是那个技术会受声音  动作和光亮的影响
but that tech still keys on sound, motion, and brightness.
因此  如果我成为
Accordingly, if I become
房间里最亮最吵的存在
the brightest and the loudest in the room,
那么我就是那些技术的唯一目标
then I'll be the tech's only target.
如果技术针对你  我们就能针对它
And if it's focused on you, we can focus on it.
飞蛾扑火
Moths to a flame.
温  你放手
Winn! Just... Just let go!
他说得对
He's right.
放手吧
Let go.
摔下去你会死的
The fall will kill you.
放手
Just let go
因为在这里
because in here...
你可以
you can!
先走一步
Leeroy Jenkins!
温  拜托  放我出去
Winn, please, just let me out
我们可以一起阻止他
and we can stop him together!
不行
No way!
即便是这个蠢货也知道你在撒谎  爸
Even this dummy knows you're lying, Dad.
他知道
He knows.
如果我被删除  你也一样
If I get deleted, so do you.
好吧  我那句改过自新  是假的
All right. When I said I changed, I lied.
我没有改变自己
I haven't changed in here,
但是我看了这里超查部的文件
but I have learned looking through the DEO's files here
也看到了你
and all the good things
为你的朋友  为世界做的好事
you've done for your friends and for the world.
我感到非常自豪  儿子
And it made me so proud, son.
我总说我们很像
I mean, I've always said that you and I are alike,
但是  我说错了
but that... that's not true.
我们几乎完全不像
No. We're almost nothing alike.
你是我最好的部分
You're simply the best part of me.
如果说  冒险有合适的时机
If there was ever a time to... to take a leap,
那就是现在
it's now.
就像我说的
And like I said,
在这里你可以做任何事  小心
in here, you can do anything. Look out!
快点  儿子
Go on, son!
输完代码
Finish entering the code.
游戏结束
Game over.
超女  他想逃跑
Supergirl, he's trying to escape!
今天可不行
Not today.
不  不  停下
No! No, stop!
爸爸
Dad?
输完代码  儿子
Finish it, son!
这是唯一的方法
It's the only way!
温
Winn?
我在这里
I'm here.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
我爸爸救了我
My dad saved me.
他说的是真话
He was telling the truth.
有时候人们会给我们惊喜
Sometimes, people can surprise us.
Q波激活
白金黑曜石实验001
很高兴看到你重新工作
Nice to see you back at work.
你怎么连接我手机的  整个房间被我屏蔽了
How did you access my phone? I have this room shielded.
只是用上我最近在研发的科技
Just a little bit of tech I've been working on.
但是我其实是想看看
But, really, I just wanted to see
你是否和安德里亚疏通关系了
if you'd sorted things with Andrea.
显然你做到了
Clearly you have.
你想听我说"谢谢你"
You know the words you want to hear me say, "Thank you."
谢谢你
Well, thank you.
你说会让安德里亚同意  而你做到了
You said you'd bring Andrea around, and you did.
很乐意帮忙
It was my pleasure.
尽管黑曜石科技
Though, it's still a mystery
一开始为什么会出故障仍是个谜
why Obsidian's tech malfunctioned in the first place.
也许这纯属巧合
I suppose it was just fortuitous
你出现在对的地方做对的事
that you were in the right place to make the right move.
是吗
Is it really?
莉娜
Oh, Lena.
干得漂亮
I am impressed.
为了你想要的东西而损害朋友
Sabotaging your friend to get what you want.
不是为了我的私欲  而是为了全人类
Not to get what I want. For the good of humanity.
当然
Ah, of course.
但是为了打败利维坦
But that is exactly the kind of thinking
我们恰恰需要这样的想法
we're going to need to defeat Leviathan.
哥哥为你感到骄傲
Your big brother is proud of you.
你应该并不想告诉我
I don't suppose my big brother
你是怎么让安德里亚同意的
wants to tell me what he did to bring Andrea around.
我和黑曜石董事会主席杰玛·库珀成为了朋友
I just made friends with an Obsidian board chair, Gemma Cooper.
多句嘴  她会是我们两个很长时间的朋友
If you ask me, she'll be a friend to us both for a long time.
告诉救世主卢瑟一家
Please tell the Anointed One the Luthors are right
就在我们计划之中
where we want them.
她会很高兴的
She will be most pleased.
这是超查部所有的氪石
Here is all the Kryptonite from the DEO.
那些是莱克斯奥服和锁定防护罩
That's the Lexosuits and the lockdown shields.
这是我们能搬来的所有东西
Everything that we could grab.
我可以把这些都送去太阳
I can still send all of it into the sun.
说到空间  艾丽克斯  我有
Speaking of space, Alex, I may have some
火星窃听技术
Martian eavesdropping tech
莱克斯可能很难发现  如果你感兴趣的话
that Lex may find hard to uncover, if you're interested.
你应该把它给布莱尼
Well, you should give it to Brainy...
因为我要离开超查部
'cause I'm quitting the DEO.
艾丽克斯  真的吗
Alex, really?
超查部到处都是莱克斯
Lex is everywhere in there,
我不能天天见到他  对他微笑
and I can't keep showing up and smiling at him,
即使是假装的
and... even if it's just pretend.
这样你就能来和我工作了
Plus, now you can come and work with me.
纳欣诺市需要高塔
National City may need the tower,
但是高塔需要领导者
but the Tower needs leaders.
会很有趣
Could be fun.
有趣又有逻辑
Fun and logical.
布莱尼  你也应该来
Brainy, you should come too.
不如就在这里工作呢
I mean, why not just work here?
讽刺的是  照这种逻辑  你必须离开
Ironically, the logic that dictates you must leave
意味着我必须留下
also dictates that I must stay...
这样才能在莱克斯身边为你们提供消息
to provide you all with eyes and ears around Lex.
你的朋友会一直支持你的  布莱尼
Your friends are always gonna have your back, Brainy.
那你呢  温  你怎样
And you, Winn, how are you?
你知道的
Oh, you know.
准备回家了
Ready to go home.
回到这里和大家重聚
Being here with you guys has, I mean...
帮了我很多
It... It's helped me
比未来更能帮到我
a lot more than the future ever could have.
你们帮我
Just... It's just helped me
走出了父亲和他的罪行
get over my dad and, you know, his crimes,
以及过去所有的阴影  所以
just my past, all of it. So...
-谢谢你们  -来吧
- Thank you. - Come on.
见到你很高兴
It's been good to see you.
好了  来吧
All right. Come here. Come here.
回头见  技术宅
Ah, we'll see you soon, Computer Lad.
不  好的  好的
No! Okay, okay.
听着
Listen.
不能再叫我技术宅  好吗
It's not Computer Lad anymore, all right?
从现在开始
From now on...
我是玩具人
it's Toyman.
温  真的吗
Winn, seriously?
是的
Yeah.
当我和你们说可以叫我
You guys, when I told you that I was okay
技术宅的时候
being called Computer Lad,
开玩笑呢  不  我讨厌"技术宅"
are you kidding me! No, I hated that. "Computer Lad."
不
No.
怎么了
What?
但是"玩具人"
But "Toyman"...
这个名字一直困扰着我
You know, that name has always haunted me.
但是如今我直面了我的父亲之后
But now after having faced my father...
他告诉我我比他更好
He told me that I was better than him.
他是对的
And he was right.
所以我要收回那个名字
So I'm gonna reclaim that name.
让它代表正义
And make it stand for good.
就像博士说的
Hey, it's like the Doctor said,
"未来由你决定"
"The future is whatever you want..."
"所以让未来变得更好吧"
"So make it a good one."
-说得好  布朗"博士"  -谢谢你
- Nice, "Doc" Brown. - Thank you.
好了  大伙们
All right, guys.
我该走了
That's my ride.
我知道你现在没法帮到莉娜
I know that you can't do anything about Lena right now,
但不要心急
but just give it time.
和威廉的感情
And with William,
你不必用谎言开始一段关系
you don't have to start a relationship with a lie.
顺其自然就行
Just see where it goes.
一步一步来
One step at a time.
我会想你的
Yeah. I'll miss you.
好的  是时候走了
Okay. That's enough.
你好  卡拉
Hello, Kara.
你好
Hello.
所以我在想
So, uh, I was thinking,
等我一下  对不起
Just one second. I'm sorry.
这是给你姥姥的
It's for your Gran Gran.
生病的姥姥
The one who was sick.
没错
Oh, right.
我奶奶
My grandma.
我奶奶说优质的拼图比抗生素更有效
My grandmother swears a good puzzle is better than antibiotics.
所以
So.
你想说什么
You were saying?
是的
Yeah.
我在想
I was thinking...
对不起  威廉  我并不喜欢你
I'm sorry, William, I just don't feel that way about you.
我理解
I understand.
我很抱歉误解了我们的关系
I'm sorry for misreading the situation.
不  不  没事的
No, no, it's fine.
回头见
I'll see you later.
好的
Yeah.
给你
There.
玩具人的永生代码
Toyman's immortality code.
我在大家都没注意时
I was able to pull the relevant sections
提取了相关部分
while everyone else was distracted.
你是个非常有用的下属  多克斯特工
You are a very useful employee, Agent Dox.
还有  我要告诉你丹弗斯局长不会再
Also, I should add Director Danvers no longer
对你或是我们的行动
poses a threat to you
造成威胁
or our operation.
很好
Perfect.
我正好收到她的辞职信
Especially as I just received her resignation.
看来要恭喜你了
So, it would seem congratulations are in order.
恭喜
Congratulations.
恭喜你
To you...
超查部局长多克斯
DEO Director Dox.
所以进展怎样
So, how did it go?
他问起了我生病的奶奶
He asked about my sick grandmother.
我只能继续演下去
And I had to go with it.
我说的第一句话就是句谎言
It was the first thing out of my mouth, and it was a lie.
然后我就离开了
And then I just... left.
我能对抗氪石驱动的莱克斯奥服
I can battle Kryptonite-powered Lexosuits,
但是我却不能迈出恋爱第一步
but I can't even take the first step in a relationship
因为一切注定毁于谎言之中
because it is doomed with deception.
你不能这么肯定
You don't know that for sure.
我和莉娜的关系就是这么结束的
Well, it happened with my friendship with Lena.
我一直忍不住想
And I can't help thinking that...
如果我做了不同的事情
if I had done things differently,
也许事情会有不同的结果
maybe things would have turned out differently.
只是  你无法知道
There is just... There's no way of knowing.
应该是荣恩带了披萨来了
Oh, that probably J'onn with the pizza,
太好了
which is great.
有人说没法知道
Some say there's no way of knowing.
但是你得先问问捣蛋鬼先生
But I say, first, ask Mr. Mxyzptlk.